[
    {
        "question": "فَأُمُّهُ",
        "answer": "His abode",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 72,
        "tlit": "fa-ummuhu",
        "frequency": "119",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأُمُّهُ هَاوِيَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُمّ",
        "waznEnglish": "mother, foundation, final abode",
        "waznTlit": "umm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "Then as for",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "fa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا مَنْ ثَقُلَتْ مَوَازِينُهُ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "But as for",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "wa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَفَّتْ مَوَازِينُهُ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَبْثُوثِ",
        "answer": "scattered",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 96,
        "tlit": "l-mabthūthi",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَكُونُ النَّاسُ كَالْفَرَاشِ الْمَبْثُوثِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ث ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَبْثُوث",
        "waznEnglish": "and dispersing",
        "waznTlit": "mabthūth",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "ثَقُلَتْ",
        "answer": "(are) heavy",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 205,
        "tlit": "thaqulat",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا مَنْ ثَقُلَتْ مَوَازِينُهُ",
        "rootWord": "ث ق ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ثَقُلَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be heavy",
        "waznTlit": "thaqulat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجِبَالُ",
        "answer": "the mountains",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 219,
        "tlit": "l-jibālu",
        "frequency": "41",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَكُونُ الْجِبَالُ كَالْعِهْنِ الْمَنْفُوشِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَبَل",
        "waznEnglish": "hill",
        "waznTlit": "jabal",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَامِيَةٌ",
        "answer": "intensely hot",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 356,
        "tlit": "ḥāmiyatun",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " نَارٌ حَامِيَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح م ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَامِيَة",
        "waznEnglish": "it will be heated [on it]",
        "waznTlit": "ḥāmiyat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَفَّتْ",
        "answer": "(are) light",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 424,
        "tlit": "khaffat",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَفَّتْ مَوَازِينُهُ",
        "rootWord": "خ ف ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَفَّتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be light",
        "waznTlit": "khaffat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْرَاكَ",
        "answer": "will make you know",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 469,
        "tlit": "adrāka",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا الْقَارِعَةُ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make known",
        "waznTlit": "adrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْرَاكَ",
        "answer": "will make you know",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 469,
        "tlit": "adrāka",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا هِيَهْ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make known",
        "waznTlit": "adrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَاضِيَةٍ",
        "answer": "pleasant",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 561,
        "tlit": "rāḍiyatin",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَهُوَ فِي عِيشَةٍ رَاضِيَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ض و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَاضِيَة",
        "waznEnglish": "will be pleased",
        "waznTlit": "rāḍiyat",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَالْعِهْنِ",
        "answer": "like wool",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1033,
        "tlit": "kal-ʿih'ni",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَكُونُ الْجِبَالُ كَالْعِهْنِ الْمَنْفُوشِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ه ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ع ه ن",
        "waznEnglish": "like wool",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn hā nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِيشَةٍ",
        "answer": "a life",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1044,
        "tlit": "ʿīshatin",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَهُوَ فِي عِيشَةٍ رَاضِيَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِيشَة",
        "waznEnglish": "a life",
        "waznTlit": "ʿīshat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَالْفَرَاشِ",
        "answer": "like moths",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1119,
        "tlit": "kal-farāshi",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَكُونُ النَّاسُ كَالْفَرَاشِ الْمَبْثُوثِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَرَاش",
        "waznEnglish": "We have spread it",
        "waznTlit": "farāsh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقَارِعَةُ",
        "answer": "The Striking Calamity",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1193,
        "tlit": "al-qāriʿatu",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الْقَارِعَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ر ع",
        "waznEnglish": "a disaster",
        "waznTlit": "qāf rā ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقَارِعَةُ",
        "answer": "(is) the Striking Calamity",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1193,
        "tlit": "l-qāriʿatu",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا الْقَارِعَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ر ع",
        "waznEnglish": "a disaster",
        "waznTlit": "qāf rā ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقَارِعَةُ",
        "answer": "(is) the Striking Calamity",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1193,
        "tlit": "l-qāriʿatu",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا الْقَارِعَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ر ع",
        "waznEnglish": "a disaster",
        "waznTlit": "qāf rā ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَكُونُ",
        "answer": "will be",
        "pcklId": "1354",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "yakūnu",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَكُونُ النَّاسُ كَالْفَرَاشِ الْمَبْثُوثِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَكُونُ",
        "answer": "And will be",
        "pcklId": "1355",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "watakūnu",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَكُونُ الْجِبَالُ كَالْعِهْنِ الْمَنْفُوشِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَنْفُوشِ",
        "answer": "fluffed up",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1501,
        "tlit": "l-manfūshi",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَكُونُ الْجِبَالُ كَالْعِهْنِ الْمَنْفُوشِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَنفُوش",
        "waznEnglish": "pastured",
        "waznTlit": "manfūsh",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَارٌ",
        "answer": "A Fire",
        "pcklId": "142",
        "rootWordId": 1529,
        "tlit": "nārun",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " نَارٌ حَامِيَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَار",
        "waznEnglish": "a fire",
        "waznTlit": "nār",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّاسُ",
        "answer": "the mankind",
        "pcklId": "234",
        "rootWordId": 1530,
        "tlit": "l-nāsu",
        "frequency": "241",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَكُونُ النَّاسُ كَالْفَرَاشِ الْمَبْثُوثِ",
        "rootWord": "ن و س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن و س",
        "waznEnglish": "the people",
        "waznTlit": "nūn wāw sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "هَاوِيَةٌ",
        "answer": "(will be the) Pit",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 1571,
        "tlit": "hāwiyatun",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأُمُّهُ هَاوِيَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ه و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَاوِيَة",
        "waznEnglish": "desire",
        "waznTlit": "hāwiyat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَوَازِينُهُ",
        "answer": "his scales",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1607,
        "tlit": "mawāzīnuhu",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا مَنْ ثَقُلَتْ مَوَازِينُهُ",
        "rootWord": "و ز ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِيزَان",
        "waznEnglish": "and weigh",
        "waznTlit": "mīzān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَوَازِينُهُ",
        "answer": "his scales",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1607,
        "tlit": "mawāzīnuhu",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ خَفَّتْ مَوَازِينُهُ",
        "rootWord": "و ز ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِيزَان",
        "waznEnglish": "and weigh",
        "waznTlit": "mīzān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "404",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "101",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَكُونُ النَّاسُ كَالْفَرَاشِ الْمَبْثُوثِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    }
]